<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Cyber Attack Learning</string>

    <string name="home_txt">One of the golden rules on the Internet is to\nnever
        share personal information with anyone.\nDespite that, cyber criminals
        can still take your\ninformation without you knowing.
        \n\nCyber Attack Learning contains information\nabout identifying
        and protection against cyber\nattacks.
        \n\nClick on the tab bar on the top of the screen to\nlearn more
        about three types of cyber attacks.</string>

    <string name="malwaretxt">Malware, short for malicious software, is a type of program or
        code that intentionally harms a computer to disrupt its normal operations and/or
        functionality. You can get malware through emails with attachments, Microsoft
        Office files, infected removable drives, sketchy websites, downloading other programs
        online in third-party sites, or from malware itself. Depending on what type of malware
        it is, it will cause harm to your computer through different methods.</string>

    <string name="malwaretypes"> Types of malware:
        \n• Adware: Irritating pop-ups ads that appear almost
        every single second. Programs adware promote may contain malicious software that users
        might download if not careful. Adware can pop up in sketchy websites on the Internet.

        \n\n• Botnet: A botnet is a network of bots—‘zombie’ computers—controlled by an
        attacker to carry out cyber attacks. malicious attachments or links to websites
        they control. Your computer can turn into a bot and be part of a botnet by clicking
        on attachments or links to websites they control, downloading malicious software,
        or through IoT devices—devices that connect and exchange data with other systems
        over communications networks.

        \n\n• Keyloggers: These are used to monitor and record what you type on your
        keyboard, both on computers and phones, which it can then save. When a hacker
        gets a record of a keyboard’s keystroke, they can extract private information.
        Keyloggers are installed through spear phishing, drive-by downloads, or through
        a trojan horse.

        \n\n• Ransomware: This restricts users’ access to a device’s data by encrypting it,
        threatening them to pay a ransom by a given date. If it isn’t paid then, the actor
        threatens to wipe the data and/or sell it off the dark web. You get ransomware on
        your devices through phishing emails with malicious attachments or drive-by downloading.

        \n\n• Spyware: A type of malware that spies on your computer activity. When spyware
        infects a device, it gathers information about the device’s owner without their
        knowledge and the creator of the spyware sells the information to third parties.
        You get spyware through clicking on adware or links to infected sites, downloads
        from unreliable websites, pirating music, movies, or games, or opening attachments
        from unknown sources.

        \n\n• Trojan Horse: Named after the Ancient Greek story of the Trojan Horse,
        this malware pretends to be a real, working program. When your computer is
        infected with this, it can act as a backdoor for other malware to come in your
        computer or download malware and disable antivirus software itself. They are
        found and spread through phishing and other social engineering tactics.

        \n\n• Worm: A computer worm duplicates itself to infect other computers while
        active in infected systems. It exploits a computer’s network or operating system
        to do  this. Compared to viruses that corrupt data and need user interaction to
        work, a worm can move by itself and usually only slows down programs or the
        computer itself. You get worms from infected systems or storage media.</string>

    <string name="malwareprotect">
        To protect yourself against malware, you can:
        \n- Check developer descriptions
        \n- Download antimalware software
        \n- Download apps or files only from trusted websites
        \n- Do not click on unverified links
        \n- Keep operating system and apps updated
        \n- Read whatever you click on </string>

    <string name="malwaresource">
        Sources:
        \n- https://thecyphere.com/blog/types-of-malware/
        \n- https://www.mcafee.com/learn/computer-viruses/
        \n- https://arcticwolf.com/resources/blog/8-types-of-malware/
        \n- https://security.berkeley.edu/faq/ransomware
        \n- https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/how-malware-can-infect-your-pc-872bf025-623d-735d-1033-ea4d456fb76b
        \n- https://www.upguard.com/blog/types-of-malware
        \n- https://www.techtarget.com/searchsecurity/definition/worm
        \n- https://www.mcafee.com/learn/understanding-trojan-viruses-and-how-to-get-rid-of-them/
        \n- https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/67735/how-do-hackers-deploy-keyloggers
        \n- https://heimdalsecurity.com/blog/all-about-botnets/
        \n- https://us.norton.com/blog/malware/spyware </string>

    <string name="virustxt">Computer viruses are a type of malware whose purpose
        is to destroy data by attaching itself to multiple files, just like
        an actual, physical virus. Hackers like to create some sort of disruption,
        thinking of it like some funny prank. But others do it to deliberately cause
        harm to other people. Through downloading files from the internet, using
        packaged/unpatched software,pen drives, clicking on email attachments or USBs
        and hard drives, the computer gets a program or file with the virus.
        When you open a file or run a program with it, the host computer gets infected.
        Then the virus starts spreading itself to other parts of the computer
        or to other computers. </string>

    <string name="virustypes">Types of viruses:
        \n- Boot sector: This type of virus destroys a computer through its
        core. It attaches itself on floppy disks, USB drives, or emails, and
        once activated, it heads straight to the master boot record and
        disrupts the computer’s startup process.
        \n\n- Self-replicated viruses that attach themselves to executable
        (.exe or .com) files which contain instructions the computer carries
        out. If users open or run an infected .exe or .com file, the virus
        replicates itself and spreads to other parts and destroys the
        computer’s memory and data.
        \n\n- Macro: These viruses are present in macro, a programming language
        normally used by Microsoft Office programs. It injects its own code
        into macros, and once activated, it can modify and/or delete files,
        slow your computer down, and corrupt your computer system.
        \n\n- Multipartite: Also called ‘multi-part viruses’, multipartite
        viruses attack both the computer’s central boot sector and files.
        This virus is attainable through .exe files and slows your computer down.
        \n\n Overwrite virus: Like its name suggests, this overwrite original data
        on infected files with random data, deeming it unusable or useless and
        unrecoverable. They spread through email attachments or file downloads
        on the Internet.
        \n\n- Polymorphic: A very advanced virus; it encrypts code with a
        different encryption key each time it replicates and spreads to another
        system to avoid antivirus software. When it gets into your computer
        through spam or downloading from infected sites, it steals personal
        information, corrupts data and slows down your computer.
        \n\n- Resident: These viruses are made to hide in a computer’s memory and
        are activated when the operating system is up and running. It can
        attach itself to antivirus software and disable its effectiveness,
        meaning it won’t be able to detect the virus, allowing the virus to
        slow the computer down.
        \n\n- Spacefiller: Also known as a ‘cavity virus’, a spacefiller is a
        virus that replicates itself, filling empty spaces in program code with
        its own malicious code. These are hard to create though, making it rare.
        The way it works is by attaching itself to executable files or email
        attachments, then spreading rapidly, destroying all computer data.</string>

    <string name="virusprotect">To protect yourself against viruses, you can:
        \n- Back files up
        \n- Do a virus scan
        \n- Don’t click on suspicious links or pop-ups
        \n- Installing virus detection or antivirus software
        \n- Using a firewall</string>

    <string name="virussource"> Sources:
        \n- https://www.buddycompany.com/post/types-of-computer-virus
        \n- https://hightouchtechnologies.com/9-common-types-of-computer-viruses/
        \n- https://logixconsulting.com/2021/06/15/what-is-a-direct-action-computer-virus/
        \n- https://www.malwarebytes.com/macro-virus
        \n- https://www.kyoceradocumentsolutions.com/in/en/about-us/blog/8-common-types-of-computer-viruses.html
        \n- https://www.trendmicro.com/vinfo/us/security/definition/polymorphic-virus
        \n- https://allaboutcookies.org/what-is-a-computer-virus
        \n- https://www.mcafee.com/learn/computer-viruses/ </string>

    <string name="scamtxt">Internet scams are internet services or software used to defraud
        or take advantage of victims for financial gain or identity theft, just like
        real-life scams. Scammers pass down information to each other. The more experience
        and information, the better they can get at scamming. They are also very good
        storytellers and actors, cunning, and use time pressure or authority against you
        in order for you to act now and give them what they want. They know exactly how
        humans act socially and use that to their advantage.</string>

    <string name="scamtypes">Types of scams:
        \n- Blackmail Scams: Blackmail scammers scare victims by threatening to leak
        private or embarrassing content from your devices if they don’t send money.
        They can be either strangers or people you know.
        \n\n- Grandparent/Imposter Scams: Scammers pretend to be people you know, like
        family or friends, or people who work for the government. They will ask you
        to transfer them money, gift cards, or ask for your personal information.
        Because of how advanced technology is nowadays, they can clone their voices
        to make it even more believable. They may also threaten you with undesirable
        consequences if you don’t comply.
        \n\n- Mail Scams: Letters you get in the mail asking you to send money or
        personal information in order to receive sweepstakes winnings, vacations,
        and more prizes are obviously mail scams. You can’t win what you never participated in.
        \n\n- Phishing: This is a type of scam where attackers send emails and text
        messages, usually online, pretending to be a business or person. They may claim
        to need you to log in a website with your personal information or transfer money
        in order to solve a problem, but be wary, as these are fake and may cause you to
        accidentally give out very private information.
        \n\n- Romance Scams: In the online dating scene, people search for others to create
        a bond with. Scammers use this to make victims fall in love with them. When the
        victim and the scammer gets into a ‘relationship’, the scammer starts asking the
        victim for money, and the victim is usually completely willing enough to give them
        the money that they need in the name of love.</string>

    <string name="scamprotect">To protect yourself against scams:
        \n- Be alert when it comes to suspicious messages
        \n- Be more cautious about connecting to public wifi or free charging stations
        \n- Be wary about who or what you’re interacting with
        \n- Don’t click on suspicious links
        \n- Don’t open texts or emails from unfamiliar people or businesses
        \n- Make sure your loved ones are actually safe
        \n- Save messages as evidence to show law enforcement</string>

    <string name="scamsource"> Sources:
        \n- https://us.norton.com/blog/emerging-threats/internet-scams
        \n- https://www.fdic.gov/resources/consumers/consumer-news/2021-10.html
        \n- https://www.welivesecurity.com/2022/05/12/10-reasons-why-we-fall-scams/
        \n- https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-are-some-common-types-of-scams-en-2092/
    </string>

    <string name="fact1">People lost $10 billion to scams\nin 2023, according to the FTC.</string>
    <string name="fact2">In 1986, the very first computer virus, a\nboot sector virus called Brain, was made.</string>
    <string name="fact3">250,000 computer viruses are\nregistered every single day of the year.</string>
    <string name="fact4">67% of ransomware attempts in the\nUS involved some form of phishing.</string>
    <string name="fact5">Cyber criminals have started using\nAI to manipulate victims better.</string>
    <string name="fact6">The most common malware file type\nreceived in 2022 were exe files.</string>
    <string name="fact7">One of the youngest hackers in the US was\nJonathan James, who hacked NASA.</string>
    <string name="fact8">Two-factor authentication alarms users of\nother devices trying to get in the account.</string>
    <string name="fact9">Products online with too-good-to-be-true\nprices are usually too good to be true.</string>
    <string name="fact10">Thoroughly reading mail you receive from\nbusinesses may prevent scams or malware.</string>

    <string name="fitbDesc">Fill in the blanks of the sentence and guess the right\nanswer!
        Contains a total of 10 questions with a\n15-question pool.</string>
    <string name="tfDesc">Answer true/false questions about malware, viruses
        \nand scams! Contains a total of 10 questions with a\n15-question pool.</string>

    <string name="fitbq1">The answer is malware1 </string>
    <string name="fitbq2">The answer is malware2 </string>
    <string name="fitbq3">The answer is malware3 </string>
    <string name="fitbq4">The answer is malware4 </string>
    <string name="fitbq5">The answer is malware5 </string>
    <string name="fitbq6">The answer is virus1 </string>
    <string name="fitbq7">The answer is virus2 </string>
    <string name="fitbq8">The answer is virus3 </string>
    <string name="fitbq9">The answer is virus4 </string>
    <string name="fitbq10">The answer is virus5 </string>
    <string name="fitbq11">The answer is scams1 </string>
    <string name="fitbq12">The answer is scams2 </string>
    <string name="fitbq13">The answer is scams3 </string>
    <string name="fitbq14">The answer is scams4 </string>
    <string name="fitbq15">The answer is scams5 </string>

    <string name="tfq1">Spyware is a type of malware.</string>
    <string name="tfq2">falsemalware.</string>
    <string name="tfq3">malware.</string>
    <string name="tfq4">falsemalware.</string>
    <string name="tfq5">malware.</string>
    <string name="tfq6">Spacefillers are rare viruses because it has a different encryption key each time it replicates.</string>
    <string name="tfq7">Resident viruses hide in a computer’s memory.</string>
    <string name="tfq8">Viruses can be avoided by using bynewalls.</string>
    <string name="tfq9">Executable files are dangerous.</string>
    <string name="tfq10">Backing files up is useless because they can be overwritten anyway.</string>
    <string name="tfq11">Scams.</string>
    <string name="tfq12">falsescams.</string>
    <string name="tfq13">scams.</string>
    <string name="tfq14">falsescams.</string>
    <string name="tfq15">scams.</string>
</resources>